ABDUL QUAWI MUHAMMED

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative self-taught React Developer years designing useful, approachable user interfaces. Knowledgeable on all aspects of Facebook's design best practices and emerging UI development techniques. Skilled at connecting exceptional assets with users via creative UI frameworks and careful user experience optimization.

WORK HISTORY

React Developer, 10/2021 - Current

Freelance, Auckland

- Created mobile applications based on React, integrating Facebook's best practices for interface design.
- Designed REST calls using React to streamline user interface performance.
- Created Netflix and Instagram clone
- Managing complete control over development and creating smooth and interactive interfaces with reusable code.

UI Developer, 09/2021 - Current

Freelance, Auckland

- Improved and expanded project platforms using JavaScript to develop rich User Interfaces.
- Incorporated fundamental and crucial UI concepts to create, user-friendly and appealing web pages.
- Designed user interfaces that engaged multiple senses and produced immersive experiences.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Improved and expanded project platforms using JavaScript to

- Auckland, AUK 1041
- **C** 02108886661
- abdul.muhammed1129@g mail.com

LINKS

- https://github.com /FrontEndFlex
- linkedin.com/in/abdul-quawimuhammed-119467205

SKILLS

- Programming
- React
- REST
- Frontend Web Development
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- NODE.js
- Communication

develop rich User Interfaces

 Designed UIs within frontend web frameworks such as React, using associated templates and tools to shorten development times

Web Developer, 01/2021 - Current

Freelance, Auckland

- Provided front-end website development using HTML, CSS & Javascript to create projects such as Dynamic web applications, pac-man and snake game and chrome extensions e.g. personal dashboard using multiple RESTful API's
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, and JSON coding

EDUCATION

Frontend Web Development, 12/2021

Self-Taught Front End Web Developer - New Zealand

CERTIFICATIONS

Frontend Web Developer- SCRIMBA Career Path